Where here advil the twenty fifteen addition I'm here with...centers how
...very good to...shake hands on the zip we should we should because they're totally not
contrived this right barely just reading just ran into each other right all while...
beating it's amazing that...both here so tell us...we...mikes what do you
...microsoft im the ba director program management responsible for...in the asher
t love the...a...infrastructure the service cloud services these sorts of things...
myself so what are the announcement that you're most excited about your built twenty fifteen
maybe have some to show is a laptop happens me hooked...well I brought it here so I might as well use
...absolutely so I'll start just a little bit of a description of what we did here we announced yesterday actually
...via blog announcement of a new api actually a template
based api that will enabled you to deploy many resources virtual
machine networkingresources neck load balance are all these things you can put them all together
in a json template now okay and deploy them all as a single unit a single click so it's that
degrades that's pretty amazing because it is
days of yours what would happen is I would startedit
wouldn't work and I would fix it and then it would work and I do the...again radio as I
still would come...would do the thing...it would work that's right that's right and then
relate well now when you do it again now you check the whole thing in exactly how we need to do it again
...fills...I'll get in here right do we have...villains I
...filled out here so why can't we can't...there's no way we get so we'll do this another that...of it so,
one of the things that we ended up...yeah, it's all template base now and, deeply integrated and
...it also deeply integrates with deploying things inside the m as well as you can run
scripts and silo so it's not just the infrastructure itself you can actually
setups inside that's the sound washed is it does it make that...does okay you
...it's really annoying actually you have some you could...I'm not sure if you things it's like open
...well so I'm here I just to show you how to find this when you're actually when
...actually going back and saying gosh, that was cool what
...I do community and templates and this...new section that we've
got guys so you can see now as...quick start templates...you can go down here you can see this
really amazing list of content here so you can kind of scroll down and see some examples here, you know,
here's...elastic...cluster of virtual machines you can look, for example,
template user beings that agnew ok so...actually go in here and pick one
scholastic search which...a full cluster...you can see parameters
...in the descriptions art supplied right now but you can see a set of parameters
what this is going to enable you to do is you can deploy multiple instances virtual
machines so on put them all together these parameters will pass out through those resources to
deploy it okay right so in this case what I'm going to do just to start off is show you a quick
deployed asher button right launch that up it goes straight into
the portal experience so it's running that script in the for now it's basically taking that template...the
...you can see here actually a new experience
...part of the portal the json template is just there it's just waiting for me now all that I
...even go in edit this if I want to rights or delete that...won't work now become a back but,
in fact you see it actually gets mad at...grills...access like that doesn't make sense so you go in here so here,
you know,
the parameters...go in and spend some time actually showing you some details on this but you're right here in the portal I can go in
and edited make updates so on so, this is a json...one actually walk through a little bit of it
was...and show you a little bit so here the very top section you can see we've got parameters so these are the things that are
coming in from the user and in this case...you can go put those parameters
...you can also passive in through the command line experience...so on which all which I'll show you
here...a bit so let me scroll down a lot of parameters you can choose the os you can choose
...load balance or type you know,...external so,
on so this deploys your for elastic search cluster lot of parameters here let's see
...standing up a whole you're not setting a machine you're setting up like the multiple
...that's right that's right so here now you go down and now you're into some variables right so this can
...things together, you know, you can build your variables out by taking some of the parameters
and building them so you can see here like the...a network settings we're going to
take some parameters that were passed in like the virtual network name and then you're going to attach the subnet
values to it so you're going to build-out your virtual network for
the software defined right you can go in can
...things so here you can see the template base url
is going to compact with shared resource that json it just puts out on the end so that you can use that in your template
...lots of our here to be able to do some really,
really impressive stuff I think the best thing is like if you're the
kind of guy or gal as your developing this infrastructure and?
You're sort of...with things up you could totally put the new adjacent file
trite check it in and when you...again you just...other thing is...are and someone
can fiddle on top of your fiddling...right and now you've got multiple fiddling less...look a whole symphony
...symphony of fiddling which...it was music to my...this one well so,
this is not as much for this is not rehearses l if it were rehearse this would be going down I think so,
here you can see as an example, you know, the actual resources that
we're going to deploy right so let me just kind of scroll down here and pick one that's perhaps an
interesting one here so let's see what should I pick me scroll down here and,
find one that's particularly...so ...I want to find the virtual network here so one
of the interesting things here that you can see being deployed here is this takes sort of the
username or password...takes a storage account and picks to regions and this is actually going to
speed up your instances...the other things that you'll see here that we'll talk about a little bit more...the in
the documentation this thing called copy index so this is a loop so what you can do here is now you can
...up multiple instances of this of this virtual machine...this node and you can you know,
first of all you'll say hey it's going to it's going to depend upon some of the shared resources that were deployed earlier and make
sure that those finish before you start here specify understand your this is like
work copying multiple instances of
...yes creating multiple is a vm so the copy indexes the way of saying this is
a loop right and you can see we name the loop and the count is actually going to
this came in as a parameter so you get to define as a customer I won ten of these I won five of the
...so the count comes in here right and then you can actually go down and the actual
the copy index which is here it's calls into the system and says what number
among so this is actually the storage account name that's being created takes from
the loop iso...name now is can carrying the account prefix...adding...number on the
...to this is a may really powerful as...because remember back of the day when we do
...more compute we just have to go to the store and buy it's like and then we had...the
...edit a role right now this is the unbelievable our right so now you can do all these things you put
them in the same availability said you've got high availability so this is all, you know,
editing in the portal let's say go savior great now I come in and now my
parameters options are ready in the portal so now I can deploy so I go in here the parameters
are ready my username password these are all the parameter just define the template right and now
they're ready for me to deploys a portsmouth someone else could take my template and just deploy it using
the parameters and they know that they've got the control tested experience that they that they want...so as a
software company you could literally build this really good software so as well I don't have
the machinery stand-up that's okay here's our custom...going-to as...and...put our software on
that's right so not only now are you able to deploy your software to
your customer right you can give...entire exact...
infrastructure right that will just work that's right and the installations that go on to the gm's and we
...to you can run the scripts on the ibm's and make that all-party a parameters
...password so now we've gone past the point of here's a cd install it
...right here here's a file what is stand-up the entire compute
...right structure and put the software on...that's right...in a preconfigured
...very cool so let me actually what I'm going to do...I'm actually going to skip over to get
hum okay because all of these templates that I just showed you actually all the ones that were in that portal
page that I showed you in...dot com actually let me go back to that time?
Click over here so here and get how we actually have a repository that we just that
we've created for this purpose that's called as...quick star templates okay and as
your dot com the page that I showed you that can had the search mechanism...found the last search
is actually pulling from this always a little script that we built that polls from the content
...here so now anyone can go build content and it'll show up in the...content as
...awesome so-and-so super so now someone as like hey, this is a respite values...a resume you put
...pork was right show up on...salami actually show ...you know,
the my favorite since of course I...course I a made it myself...
I made right so what this one does and I'll actually it's you see it's actually in the repository
under...as a quick...templates and I can go in and here's the json file so similar
sort of story set of parameters a pass through right and then of course here's and this only...of
one vm so it's a little bit less complex size...account public ip virtual network so this is
...network in the neck so I'm actually spinning up the...here and then...I
...virtual machine years name and password the interesting thing here what I'm doing this uses the
doctor extension that we've that we that we build and
...does it pulls the latest doctor engine down right on this
...xbox and actually installs these images that are from doctor hub so in this case
...parameters so you could say, you know, I want, you know, I want and,
...install I one...is to install right and you'll pass that through as parameters will spin
up the vm bring down the doctor engine and put those containers on the box in one
swoop but wait there's more islip I saw...you go back there was a
deployed as...love to go back, yeah, so, here you can see the parameter the options right so, yeah, so,
I go back deployed asher and...name experience it goes all the way back you can
deployed directly from that get hub experience right back into this experience that's from
...now goes back to the portal right and let's say I'm not going to change I like what I've got here I had
saved and then you can see my parameters and like I said, you know, and,
in fact I have the default values there if you want to just use engine
...read mongolia away you got so if you're if you're the type that likes to experiment
with new-style absolutely you could totally stand-up like experimental environment
right of a certain...and do whatever kind of test you want...that's right that's exactly right, yeah,
that's exactly that's exactly the case so it allows you to sort of build on that and let me actually go back to
this template thing this page...dot com to sort of show what I meant about this being index so
all search for doctor here and there there's, you know, there's my might the one that I built-in you can see up here in the
upper-left pulls from get hub the picture that so there's might...you know, my ugly bug up there
on the left that's the upper-left so this will make it so people can search...you can find this and,
you can I go to point later so here's a question, yeah, is it when it's deploying this is a deploying
into its own resource group or how does that workbecause there's...there's a notion of resource group
...regroup stuff together...right how does this do this, yeah, great question so when you deployed that
portal experience it does deploy to a new resource group that's basically generated on your behalf and,
it all spin up the resources within it right so, for that experience yes it ends up being sort of
its own dedicated research group through our show or through the
...alive which I actually can show you now I want to you can actually
...to other resources you have a lot more control there you can crayon research group you can
...its other ones so actually maybe I'll take this as
...there's a computer here...you're here I might as well as do it so let's actually go over here and I'm
actually I'm running here actually in my in my get hub experience but I do that just because I use
...right can zoom in a little...let's see or does you know,
what my zoom it's not on hold on one...you shy install...real...it was...
the right whereas it I added up here okay should I go all the way here let's go all the
...man we might as well doing this live here
...this isn't going to work for me this isn't going to work from you guys?
All right let's do...says a...that's a better idea, you know, I
like the way you think sometimes I have a really good thoughts...
In this house that is that...too big nativity big aren't so great so
...actually in the get...prompt and the reason why do this is actually the way I do sh so, I'm going to
actually sh into a...you want to into a exactly, exactly...look at my
passable...going to actually system research required well let me get this done quickly here what
I can do is I'm actually running...boxes running in...and the reason why I'm here...I want to show the...
with which runs cross platform right so well actually do here is I'm going to pull down
whoops let's see here that is the latest one I'm going to pull down the latest
...I we...container that makes the super easy to run cool right so I've got the
...I'm going-to go ahead and log in here oops?
So, this...it's the latest...and, it pulls down... right away I can go in and use my
...here to login.
Okay, abc one-two-three...cat now you can see...
Okay, yeah, okay, that's it that's it I think I got...so,
what this does this...into my account so now I'm using the full command line experience right I can do
any sort of thing I can I do the normal sort of add the m all using the new api but I can actually
...copy these down a little bit of...your guys no way ...boring gallons
...copy so I'm going to do here is actually move out of this new mode for the api so,
this is sort of a new it's arm agile resource manager mode so here like
you asked now I can actually make it more specific right I mean actually name my resource group so that's
...rgb right so all name...in west us into a little bit more control now
...take these templates and apply them to a resource
invert exif exactly so in this case I've already I'm going to create a resource group so this is calling
back and hopefully connectivity connectivity works here so while that's coming
in all actually show you what I'm going to run here so this is also a little bit smaller than
...let's see here format font let's zoom this...perfect so what I'm actually going
to do here is I'm actually going to run as a group create so what this does is it will create this deployment is going to
created in the...argue that I'm that I'm creating right nowand,
actually can pull straight from get up so it's the same that what the template
...in get hub it now pulled it down so this...deploys simple linux vm right
...another...that I built right so, you know, it's good, yeah, it's...be, you know, what I got feeling right and,
this pulled it straight from there and can deployed right so it's amazing how...just take
...the group is created all actually launch that and there's going to be some parameters most
likely right so let me see up there's a parameter requests and those are the same parameters that is
real-world that's right exactly right so now I can I could also passes in
a scripting options so I could script the whole thing right in this case all, you know, go and say look
khoury demo one
the username or passwordabc...now you...it actually look away
look away the dns name so this also has to be sort of a unique dns names all say, you know,
this announce away we go so to actually create those deployments
...some e-mail clearly ...doing that is right and,
wait for those complete you can...creating storage going to create a neck
...vm and then it also...vm for me using the extension model
...we go that's...story to say look running on linux when it
comes to computing you can you could work on the software we can stand-up anything you want
...everyone that's right that's...any other announcements if you want to talk about and closing,
yeah,...like, you know, this is great and I mean I think the thing that we really love about it's really enable a
lot of new partnerships as well as so, this new api
it's so powerful and it's so great what we're seeing a lot of excitement in fact we nancy's as well yesterday
...new partnership with confounding a who will be building on top of this j elastic who we building on top of this
...as well that's so, they're building some great stuff we've got working with the
...we got doo-doo also being a able to deploy on top of this and the scalar as well butand,
then write scale so we just a ton of partners and really exciting stuff
...all of really built around this new this new model all json
base very open very easy-to-use and...my friends can be a...well make your own
template submit polar question they'll show up as dot as a within as
...dot com now anyone can find them you can go search for them and, a way you go so...the best
write make you're the one that people want to use a on top of measure thanks so much for spending some time I
loaded man it was great...works...what's...I could you ask for so at least take a look at these things
and, if you have any questions you can always look you up work that's right, yeah, so, you can find me at twitter
which is at...standards...and make sure...it so it send all the twists...
Yet and but, no, commons about fiddle that's what we're going to we're not going to
do any symphonies of fiddling on top of twitter all right it's got super awkward idaho's
...not to but known...the perfect amount this is really good banter this is
really this...real we can actually start to show, yeah,the real gentleman
...so, you're...love it will thanks for watching we'll see you next time guys take care I thanks-a-lot.